Morning. Cassie.
Glad you could join US.
Sorry I'm late.
Hi.
Good morning. Kid's late again.
Okay. you have a good day.
Mr. Rodriguez.
Thanks. You. too.
Hey. what took you so long? I thought
you left the house right after me.
I did.
Traffic was unbelievable.
Okay. I'll log you in.
Go get your drawer.
No. Mom. please.
I got it.
Cassie. honey. I know you
want to stay up all night
and talk with
your friends online.
but you can't come in here
20 minutes late all the time.
Mom. this is. like. the second
time this has ever happened.
Just relax.
Actually. it's the third.
If it happens one more time.
Mr. Crenshaw's gonna let you go.
He said that? Why doesn't
he just tell me to my face?
Because I'm the one that
convinced him to hire you.
That is so passive-aggressive.
Unit 6. what's your 20?
Unit 6 at union and west kalmia.
Okay. you may not need
this job. but I do.
Oh. so I'm making you look bad?
Is that what you're saying?
If I'm such an embarrassment to you.
then why do you force me to work here?
Force you? Do you know how
many kids your age are out of work?
Besides. I thought you wanted
to save for college.
You know. lately.
I don't know about college.
You promised me you would
enroll at the j.C. This fall.
Maybe I changed my mind.
When are you gonna get serious?
Here we go again.
You don't want to work.
You don't wanna go to college
like the rest of your friends.
Look. I don't care what you do
with your time.
Just find something
Anything you're
passionate about  and do it.
Mom. can we talk
about this at home?
I'm at work.
Ugh! You remind me
so much of your father
it's not even funny.
Look...
Turn around. What  no.
Your hair's i don't need your help!
Your name tag's upside down.
Mom. I didn't mean it.
I just...
I'm sorry.
You're right.
It's just...
Sometimes I forget.
What? That you're all grown up.
Look. I know it's corny.
but to me. you're...
Always gonna be my baby girl.
I can help who's next in line.
It's not corny.
Oh. God. Mom
We're being hit!
Don't shoot!
Don't shoot! Mom
Go!
Move!
Step away from the counters. now!
Stay down!
Stay down. Stay
down. Open the door!
Three seconds.
and I'll shoot him!
Nobody move!
Take out your cell phones. now!
Toss them on the
floor! All of them!
All the phones!
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Do it!
All right. Everybody into the vault.
Let's go.
Go.
go. go! Go! Get up!
Move it!
Let's go! Go. go. go. go. go!
Go. go! Faster!
Go! Hurry up!
Wait a minute.
You come with me. Mom!
- Get in there!
- Stay there! Mom!
Get over here.
Please don't hurt them.
Please. I'll do whatever you want.
You do everything I say. exactly
how I tell you. Okay. Yeah.
Move it!
Are you crazy?
My daughter's out there.
They'll shoot you both.
I'll take my chances.
Now give me that key!
Hurry up! All of
it. Put it in the bag.
Right on time.
Let's go.
Listen to me.
Go outside and let them in.
Do whatever you normally do.
Don't try to give
them any kind of funny signal.
'cause if you do.
I'll shoot you in the back.
Go!
Good morning. Cassie. Good morning.
How's your day going? Really good.
You?
Another day giving 100%
to the top 1%
so they can keep me
in the bottom 10%.
How's your mom? She's good.
That woman deserves a promotion.
Five years working
for this company.
and I bet she hasn't missed
a single day.
Kind of makes you wonder
why the hell we even do this crap.
Where is everybody?
Bob. please.
they have my daughter.
I cannot just stay in here.
What if it was your daughter?
- Hurry up.
- Gotta make sure.
Hey. John. you all clear?
Hey. John. do you copy?
Give me the "all clear." buddy.
Bob. please.
I'm sorry. I can't.
Give me that key!
Dispatch.
officer's radio is 10-3.
I'm going inside
to check it out.
Where are you going?
Put the money in the bag!
Hurry up! Go!
Robbery in progress.
Shots fired.
Copy that.
unit 6. Police en route.
The zipper's stuck. What?
You kidding me?
Why are you doing this?
Let's go.
Oh. watch out.
What are you doing? Be careful.
Whoa. Whoa. whoa.
Watch out.
Get in the back of the Van. quick!
No. don't!
What the hell is the matter with you?
Stop it!
Take it easy!
Come on! Stop it!
Wait a second.
I've seen you before.
From school.
You graduated last year.
She didn't graduate.
She got kicked out.
Grace?
Hi. Cassie.
Why is she here?
She recognized me.
Oh. that's great.
Just great.
Are you out of your mind?
What the hell is going on?
How much you get?
Probably twice as much as
we expected. but so what?
A hostage. Abbie?
Seriously?
I had to. She was not
part of the plan.
Yeah? Well. bringing live ammo
wasn't part of the plan. either.
Wait. You did that? Yeah. And she
shot the guy from the armored truck.
Oh. my God. We killed somebody.
We didn't kill him.
He was moving when I
ran out of the truck.
I can't believe it.
We're screwed!
Everybody just chill. okay?
We're not screwed.
It's a black market gun.
I made sure to cover my ass.
unlike Abbie over here.
who stupidly decided
to bring her best friend along
Her best friend
who's gonna talk.
She won't.She knows US.
She will.
What were you thinking. Joyce?
You could've got US all killed.
Good morning.
ladies and gentlemen.
I am f.B.I. Agent
Christine mendoza.
and I'm gonna be leading
this investigation.
which means I'm gonna have to
speak to each and every one of you.
So please don't leave
the premises.
Folks. I'm detective barker.
Please have a seat in the
sterile holding area over here.
Detective. I'm Joyce aveson. If
you need medical help
My daughter ma'am. please.
We'll be with you in a moment.
Just take a seat. They kidnapped
my daughter.
Come with me.
I swear to god.
if you tell the cops I did this.
I'll tell them you helped Abbie plan this
whole thing. which you practically did.
Knock it off!
We hold Cassie until tonight.
That'll give US time.
You can go get out of the state.
and I can do what I gotta do.
What the hell are you doing?
Taking the back way.
The cops will be looking for US
on the main road.
What does she mean.
that I helped you plan this?
Abbie. what does
she mean by that?
Forget it.
The less you know. the better.
Don't listen to Marie.
She's full of crap. Watch your mouth.
Wait just a minute.
So a couple weeks ago.
when you were asking me all
those questions about the bank
My schedule.
how many employees are there.
the vault. what time
the armored truck arrives
I thought that you
just wanted a job.
I was trying to help you.
And you sure as hell did.
Shut up. Marie!
I trusted you.
I'm sorry.
And you set me up.
How could you guys
do this to me?
Cassie. take it easy.
Why. Abbie? I had to!
Grace. stop the van right now.
I'm getting out.
Okay. cool. So you're gonna
let her call the shots now.
Is that what
you're gonna do. grace?
Grace! Cassie. calm down!
Grace. do it now!
Cassie
Oh. my God!
An armored car driver was shot
this morning..
..as two heavily armed men
wearing ski masks..
..held up the palm vista bank..
..here on the 2300 block
of El cajon boulevard..
..in downtown San Diego.
The robbery happened
right around 9:30 A.M..
just under an hour ago.
Fortunately. the driver
sustained only minor bruising
due to the bulletproof vest
he was wearing at the time.
According to the bank's manager.
the two masked men escaped with
an undisclosed amount of money
and were last seen driving
away from the bank in a green van.
Must be nice to work with y
our daughter.
It is.
I got her the job to spend more
time with her.
Her dad died of colon cancer
when she was ten.
Sorry to hear that.
I haven't really been there for her.
Maybe I was the reason she was
getting into trouble at school.
What kind of trouble?
Oh. she was suspended.
For what?
Fighting.
Takes after her mom.
Well. I hear this morning in the vault.
you and your boss got into it.
Yeah. I was trying to help Cassie.
So you interrupted
an armored car driver
who attempted to stop the getaway?
Yes. He was aiming
toward my daughter.
I understand how
you feel. I'm sorry.
As a mother. I believe I have
the right to protect my child.
But you forget.
these armored car drivers
are trained to handle
the situation.
Do you have children.
Ms. Mendoza?
No.
Well. then. forgive me when
I tell you that you're wrong.
Because there's no possible way
you could understand how I feel.
Mendoza.
We got the surveillance video
cued up.
Please stay put.
Is everybody okay?
I need help.
Easy. I think I messed up my leg.
Okay.
You okay?
Cassie!
Cassie. stop!
Cassie! Cassie!
Get off of me! Cassie. please stop!
This is how
you pay me back? What?
For last semester
in the locker room?
I can't even believe
you're bringing that up.
I got suspended for fighting. for
defending you. and this is how you thank me?
This is the thanks I get?
You almost killed US.
Marie i ought to pop you
right now!
Come on. Take it easy. I told you
she'd try to run to the cops.
She can't afford to.
Like you said.
if she goes to the cops.
we'll say she was in on it.
We'll say she's the insider.
But that'll never happen.
because she's gonna
do what I say.
Right. Cassie?
Right.
Grace and Abbie
They might be your friends.
Don't confuse them with me.
Come on.
Okay. now check this out.
Freeze.
Does that look weird to you?
Yeah.
Play it again.
Right there.
She says something.
Why are you doing this?
What do you think?
I think I'm gonna go talk
to the mother again.
We need to pull everything
out of the van and wipe it down.
You do that.
I'm getting my money.
I  I think I broke my leg.
The bone is popping out. I am
so sorry I grabbed the wheel.
I should never have done that.
Shut up.
Take this.
Start picking up
the money. Go.
Abbie. we gotta get outta here.
Yeah. No kidding. Someone might see US.
I got it handled.
How?
I said I got it handled.
Go.
A moment prior.
she's cowering in fear.
Then. suddenly she stands.
and they stare at each other
for nearly ten whole seconds.
Now. I'm no psychologist.
but I'd say given the proximity.
they seem pretty comfortable
with each other.
That could mean anything.
You have no idea
the emotional hell she was
going through at that moment.
Actually. I do. Were you there?
He was aiming a gun
at her. point-blank.
Ms. Aveson. I spent
ten years at the border
during the Mexican drug wars.
El Paso. matamoros. Tijuana.
I've seen more
than my fair share
of hostage situation. kidnapping
attempts and beheadings.
Great resume.
You wanna impress me?
Find my daughter.
I think they know each other.
What? It adds up.
Body language.
the way they talk to each other.
ten seconds
of visual recognition.
You have got to be kidding me.
A dozen people in a vault.
Your daughter is the only one
chosen to empty the cash drawers
and escort the courier
from the armored car.
They grabbed the last
person to go into the vault.
That just so happened
to be Cassie.
You show me a video
of these bastards
sticking a loaded gun
into my baby girl's face.
and then you try and tell me
that she's working with them.
Are you crazy?
We'll talk about this later.
Please excuse US.
Let me check yours.
Abbie. We'll do it later.
Don't worry.
You'll get your cut.
My god. Marie!
You called your boyfriend?
What did you tell him?
Everything.
I kind of had to.
That was not part of the plan.
Baby. baby!
Nobody's supposed to know about this!
Come here.
You all right?
Let's see
what you got. Oh. my God.
Oh. yeah! That's what
I'm talking about. Whoo!
Hey. Nick.
How'd you get here so fast?
You live across town.
A shortcut.
Who's this little sport-rocket?
Shut up.
She's not your type.
Let's go.
Bye.
We have to get her
to a hospital now. I know.
Come on. God. let's get
the hell out of here.
Up you go.
Come on.
We gotta get somewhere.
I got you. Come on. come on. come on.
Come on. Yeah!
Okay. Be careful.
Yeah! Whoo!
What's taking her so long?
She's probably updating
her Facebook page.
"Hey. everybody.
I just robbed a bank!
O.m.g.! So much fun!"
You're not funny. Nick.
So. why is it that
they brought you along?
Your driving skills?
Oh. kiss my ass.
Abbie needed help.
I was the first person
she called.
Was this worth the money?
We didn't do it for the money.
Hey!
I think they know each other.
Whoo!
Wow. Nice.
When can we take her
to the emergency room?
Don't worry about it. Abbie.
you do what you have to do. okay?
I promise I will get you there
as soon as I possibly can.
Okay.
That's them.
Hello. Abbie.
You got the money?
It's right here.
Bueno.
Where's my dad?
Daddy.
I'm okay. honey.
They hurt you.
It looks worse than it is.
Are you all right?
I did what they asked.
What?
Oh. my God.
Where did you get all that?
Don't worry about it.
I'm gonna bring you home. okay?
Just be strong
another couple of hours.
Abbie. what did you do?
Dad?
You bring $500.000 a coyote pass.
off highway 98.
12 miles east of ocotillo.
You park at the road block.
then hike in half a mile.
Okay.
At the old water tank.
you're gonna see a road.
Wait for US there.Okay.
4:00. You come alone.
No cops.
Do exactly like I say. or he dies.
Oh. and I'm gonna keep your
papa's computer. I like it.
Hey. I just got a call
from the station.
It looks like they might
have found the getaway Van.
Where's the mom?
Haven't seen her.
So how did it happen?
You know how my dad does real
estate in foreign countries?
Three weeks ago.
he went down to Tijuana.
He said they grabbed him
right off the street.
Drug cartel. mafia...
I have no clue who they are.
But they called me and told me
that I had to give them a
half a million dollars by today.
or they would kill him.
Pretty good scam.
if you ask me. Who's asking?
Ow. ow. ow.Sorry.
Why didn't you
just go to the police?
You heard what he said.
If I go to the cops.
they will kill him.
Aren't they in Mexico? I mean.
how would they even know?
They told me that
if I tell the cops.
the cops will tell the feds. and the
feds will tell the Mexican government.
and they would find out.
because they have people
working inside
the Mexican government.
Okay. so. why didn't you
just use your own money?
Your father's. like.
a millionaire. right?
This house alone
must be worth. like zip.
Mortgaged to the hilt.
My dad lost everything
in the recession.
We have nothing.
Boo-hoo.
Poor little rich girl. forced
to live like the rest of US.
Ever since I lost my mom.
it's just been me and my dad.
I didn't have anybody else
to turn to.
Why didn't you just come to me
instead of doing all this
behind my back?
If I had. would you have
helped me Rob the bank?
That is 370.000 United States
currency. baby.
and that's just
what's in this bag.
Whoo! Give me the bag
so I can check the rest of it.
Let go. Marie. No. you let go.
What was that?
Someone pulled
in front of your house.
It's Cassie's mom.
Mom grace
She saw me!
Hurry up!
Put Cassie in the bedroom!
Nick. get the money
off the table!
You kidding me? I just finished
stacking this up. Nick. now!
No. I don't think so.
Bring me the other bag.
I'll count it. Abbie!
Hurry up! Go! Now! Freaking kidding me.
Come on. come on. come on!
Abbie!
I know you're in there!
Easy.
Please open this door.
If you say a word you're dead.
If your mom walks through that door
right now. I'm gonna shoot her in the face.
Abbie!
Ow!
Here. Right there.
Abbie. I need to talk
to you now. please.
You know that I saw you.
Please open this door.
What are you doing?
Abbie!
Everybody be really quiet.
Hi. Joyce.
Good morning.
Hi. Abbie. I don't suppose
your dad's home?
Mm-mm. He's on
a business trip. Why?
Where's Cassie?
W  um. she's not here.
Abbie. don't lie to me.
I'm not lying.
Is Cassie in some kind
of trouble or something?
I don't know.
Is she?
You're really starting
to scare me. What is going on?
I think you know
exactly what's going on.
I do? Because i Cassie!
What  hang on! Cassie!
Wait  no. She's with
you. right? She's working today.
Stop with the act. I know
you were at the bank today.
Where is she?
At the bank? She's not at the bank.
You took Cassie hostage. What?
I could've told the police.
I didn't.
All I want is my daughter.
Please. Where is she? Joyce. slow down.
I saw a big
roll of plastic in the garage.
We dig a hole in the desert.
get rid of both of them.
Shut up.
What is that?
This is a still frame
from security video at the bank.
This is the wrist of the person
who robbed US this morning.
My god. are you okay?
Was anybody hurt?
Abbie. stop it.
I was with Cassie
when she bought that for you.
A million people
have bracelets like that.
Cut the bull!
No offense.
but are you on. like.
some kind of medication
or something?
Because none of this
makes any sense.
A few weeks ago. Cassie
told me you were asking her
a lot of questions
about her job.
Yeah?
Why were you so curious?
Joyce. be real.
Do you really think that I'm the
kind of girl who would Rob a bank?
You're telling me that you have
been here all morning. alone?
Yeah.
Prove it.
I guess you're just gonna
have to take my word for it.
No. I'm gonna look
in every room in this house.
I'm gonna go out there
and shoot her right now. Wait. wait.
Cassie? Get in the bathroom.
Get in the bathroom.
Cassie. are you back here?
Wait! Joyce. wait!
Ms. Aveson. please!
Cassie.
are you back here? Wait!
Oh. Hey.
Baby. what's going on?
Um...
This is. um...
This is my friend's mom.
Oh. hi. I'm Jack.
Babe. why don't you
go back to bed?
I'll be in in a minute.
Are you sure? Yes.
Mm.
I love you.
I love you. too.
I can't get enough of this.
I'm sorry I lied.
I wasn't alone.
Please don't tell my dad.
I guess I owe you an apology.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. You've been
through a lot this morning.
What about Cassie?
Do the police have any idea
where they took her?
No. not yet. Um...
The cops said that
once the bank robbers
get far enough away.
they usually let the hostage go.
But I guess I'll just
have to wait and see.
I'm really sorry.
What's this?
Coyote pass off highway 98?
Oh. that's just
a message for my dad.
Some guy called about some kind
of development out in the desert.
I'll have to remember
to give that to him.
I'll let myself out.
She's gone!
Go!
Hey. that's twice today
I've saved your bacon.
Least you could do
is say "thank you."
I'm not sensing
gratitude right now. No.
I think Abbie needs to
learn that it's better to give
than receive.
Abbie...
We're taking it all.
We had a deal. I changed the deal.
Marie. please.
Between your bag and mine.
I'm sure we've got over
a million dollars right now.
Our agreement was to keep
everything over 500.000.
That's not enough for you?
I've expensive taste.
Okay. what about Abbie's dad?
You saw what they did to him.
If they don't get the money they
asked for. they're gonna kill him.
That's Abbie's problem; Not mine.
Let's go.
I say we kill all three of them.
cover our tracks.
It's not required. What if they talk?
Then they'll get 30 to life
for armed robbery.
They're stupid.
but they're not that stupid.
Come on. Let's hit it.
Marie.
Come on.
You think you're better
than me. don't you?
Come on.
What's happening? We need to get
outta here right now.
Why? Because Nick and Marie
are gonna be back any second.
and this time. they will kill US.
Move.but...
Mm.
When we get
to the hotel in Reno.
I'm gonna throw this money
all over the bed.
Oh. yeah? Mm-hmm.
And then I'm gonna
throw you on top of it...
And then
I'm gonna take off my...
What the hell is this?
You gotta be kidding me.
I'm gonna kill her!
Cassie. I'm gonna drop you off a
couple blocks away from the hospital.
I know that I have no right
to ask you for a favor.
but can you please wait
to talk to the cops
until after 4:00?
Just give me that time
to get my dad back.
Can you promise me that? Yes. Yeah.
I'm just worried about
Abbie. let's go.Okay.
We're gonna take my dad's car
so grace can fit in the back seat.
Hold on.
hold on. hold on. Damn it!
The car is gone!
Check upstairs.Yeah.
They're not here.
So what exactly did you see?
Well. there were four women
who came from the Van.
and then they walked
up that hill. and...
A brown truck arrived.
and a man stepped out.
and then everyone got in.
They drove off.
Women? You're sure?
Yes. I'm pretty sure I know
what a woman looks like. dear.
What age were they?
Well. the guy
was in his late 20's.
and the girls were college age.
High school. maybe.
And what ethnicity were they?
Well. they were all white.
except one girl
was African-American.
Looks like she'd broken a leg.
They were helping her walk.
This is a long shot.
but any of the girls
look like this?
You know. I was standing
all the way over there.
I'm not sure...
Yes. Possibly.
Yes. one girl did look like her.
Okay.
Thank you. Mrs. Wells.
Agent mendoza. before you leave.
maybe you could help me.
I'm looking for someone.
His name is Gary.
Gary Wells.
He's seven years old.
He should be back by now.
but I haven't seen him yet.
I'm very. very worried. and I
want you to look for him. please.
Okay. I'll do that.
I'll wait for your call.
All right. I want you to alert
every emergency room in the area
to be on the lookout
for an African-American girl.
18 to 25. with a sprained
ankle or a broken leg.
Whoa. Wait a minute. You don't
actually believe what she said?
My grandfather was the same way.
One second. he'd be sharp.
The next second. he'd be...
Floating off to another planet.
Not gonna hold up in court.
How did you
know they would Rob you?
I didn't.
But when we flipped the Van.
Nick came to pick US up
way too fast.
And then when we got home.
I saw footprints in the house.
and the back door was unlocked.
I always lock that door.
My guess is.
while we were robbing the bank.
Nick broke into the house
and was waiting
to ambush US when we got there.
But then Marie called him
to come pick US up. Yeah?
Come get US. We crashed the Van.
You what?
You heard me! You got the money.
right?
Shut up. and get over to the old
dirt road!
Yeah. I'll be right there. Regardless.
he and Marie were planning
to screw me over all along.
So while you guys were
waiting outside in the car.
I counted the cash. and I put it
underneath the bathroom sink
and replaced it with
my dad's paperback collection.
Hello. This is Joyce.
Mrs. Aveson. this is detective
mendoza.
I've got some new evidence
involving your daughter.
What is it?
I'd like to discuss it in person.
Can you meet me at the f.B.I.
Headquarters on 3rd street?
One last favor:
When you talk to the police.
leave grace's name out of it.
Um. hello! Thank you.
Cassie. I don't have that long.
Are you really gonna go talk to the
kidnappers without any protection at all.
..like a gun or anything?
Do I have a choice?
I mean. my life's over.
I'm gonna go to jail either way.
But I'm gonna try to get
my dad back first.
I'll see you later.
Okay.
I'm coming with you.
Cassie just shut up and drive.
So when do you think this happened?
According to eyewitnesses.
the car crashed at about 10:30 A.M..
45 minutes after the robbery.
But by the time we got there.
the car was already abandoned.
Do you know if Cassie was with them?
Somebody who looks like
your daughter was seen there.
along with a man
in his late 20's
and three girls
approximately Cassie's age.
one of whom had a broken leg.
Ms. Aveson. three teenage girls
robbed your bank this morning.
The reason I called you
in here today
is 'cause I need to talk to you
about Cassie's friends.
I'm gonna need a list from you
of names. e-mail addresses
No. Cassie's friends are
all going to college.
Trust me. they're not spending
their summer break robbing banks.
Are you sure about that?
Tell you what. um. why don't
you give me a list of names.
and I'll confirm whether Cassie
knows them or not.
That's the way it's supposed to work;
Isn't it? I'm just trying to help you.
The best thing you can do
right now for your daughter
is give me as much information
as possible
so that "a" we can find her.
and "b" we can rule out any
connection with the bank job.
And if I don't?
Well. then. the evidence just
stacks up against the both of you.
Excuse me?
That little stunt
you pulled this morning
with the armored car driver.
covering up for her now
How do I know
you're not the insider?
How do I know you're not
orchestrating this whole thing?
Okay.
I get it.
And now I won't
be discussing this
any further with you
without a lawyer.
Please. it's just
a list of names.
That's all I'm asking.
So what happened to you?
I was hiking. and I guess I wasn't
watching where I was going.
Okay. on "three."
One. two. three.
I guess you're not
gonna do that again.
Thank you.
You watch her back. okay? Yeah.
Ortho room.
Wet-to-dry dressing.
Come on.
Ladies.
Hi. I'm gonna need you both
to fill out some forms.
Can't grace just do that? This is for
insurance purposes.
They're gonna want as many
third-party statements as possible.
Why don't you have a seat. and I'll go get
the paperwork? We don't really have time.
It's only gonna take a minute.
It's gonna help your friend out.
Okay.
We'll come back later.
Excuse me. ladies.
Can I have a word with you
in my office. please?
Uh... uh. what's wrong?
I just need to ask you
a few questions.
Why? Just routine.
Nothing to worry about.
Please.
Follow me. We just came
to drop off our friend.
The getaway van was found overturned
and abandoned...
I'm sorry.
I can't let you do that.
On the security camera. where
we can see one of the robbers
stuffing the money
into a green duffle bag.
The robbers left with one of
the bank employees. and...
Run! No. they were here.
They just ran by my security
officer.
Go. go. go!
Out of the
way! Move it! Move it!
Out of the way!
Whoa  what  watch out.
Get out of the
way! Get out of the way!
Come on! Come on!
Okay.
Let's hurry up.
Yeah. Security tried to stop them.
but they got away.
Okay. Thanks. I'm on my way
to the hospital right now.
All right.
See you soon.Okay.
What? Is it them?
They call from
a different number every time.
Hello? Hey. chica.
We just watched
American t.V.
Somebody robbed the Palm Vista
National Bank
and got away with a million
dollars in a green bag.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You think
iestupido? I tell you what I think.
I think you got a million
dollars. and you're not telling US.
I don't have a million.
I have 600.000 or so.
but that's it.
The price just went up.
You wanna see your papa alive.
you meet US at the border in 90
minutes. you bring US a million dollars.
You can't do this.
I did what you asked.
One million.
Don't be late.
or I chop off his head.
Gracias.
What did they say?
Abbie. what is going on?
I did what they told me to do.
I pull of the impossible. and then they
change the rules at the very last minute?
Well god. those sons of bitches!
Now they want a million dollars.
There's nothing I can do.
My dad's gonna die. and there's
nothing I can do.
No. No. He is not
gonna die. okay?
We'll get the money. How?
We can't Rob your bank twice.
Can we?
Her name's cassieaveson.
She goes to your high school.
Do you know her?
I know of her. We're not friends.
if that's what you're asking.
That's interesting. because the
admitting nurse and the security guard
said that this girl
was the girl who admitted you
in this hospital
less than an hour ago.
They're mistaken. My friends
Barbara and Nancy dropped me off.
Really? So why do you
think Nancy and Barbara
ran from the security guards?
Sometimes they smoke a little weed.
Maybe they had some on them
and didn't wanna get busted.
Where'd you go hiking
this morning? Torrey pines.
You sure you weren't here?
'Cause my witnesses said
that Cassie was helping an
African-American girl with a broken leg
out of a van this morning that
just so happened to be the same Van
used in the getaway
at the bank robbery.
How long you gonna
play this game. grace?
You're a smart woman.
School principal says
you're going to Stanford.
gonna be a lawyer.
Good for you.
You should know better than to get
messed up in something like this.
I know you were with Cassie
this morning.
Who else?
Come on. grace.
If you cooperate with me. that's
gonna take the edge off. you know?
It's your first offense. You're
gonna do a short sentence.
But if you don't. I'm gonna
make sure you do hard time
for armed robbery
and attempted murder.
Do you understand
those legal terms. counselor?
All right.
I'll talk.
Okay. Good.
All right.
Start with this morning.
I wanna know everything.
Go.
I. um...
I woke up.
Did some reading.
"No person shall be held
to answer on a capital.
or otherwise infamous crime.
unless on a presentment
or indictment
of a grand jury."
Fifth amendment?
I'm not gonna say.
Just shut up. all right?
I'm sick of hearing about it.
You were holding it. All
you had to do was look inside.
We bagged 370.000. all right? We're
going to Reno. just like we planned.
I want the rest of it. We know
where Abbie's gonna be at 4:00.
I'm not mixing it up
with pancho villa
and his band
of mariachi mutilators.
All right? I won't.Well. I've
got it all figured out. so..
If you did. I don't wanna hear about it.
One honk. I go in;
And two. you get out of there.
Okay? Okay.
Listen to me!
We get to the border early.
We grab the cash from Abbie
before the kidnappers show up.
There isn't enough time!
I wanna be on the road in the next
30 minutes. just like we planned.
Pack your stuff.
Douche face.
I thought I said
I wasn't talking to you.
Grace Miller. 18
years old. African-American.
senior editor
of the school newspaper.
That ring a bell? Um...
She's at the adobe park hospital
medical center with a broken leg.
My guess is she probably broke her leg
when the van flipped. Part of the robbery.
I've been trying to get her to
talk for the last 20 minutes.
and she's not saying anything.
That's why I called you.
Is Cassie friends with grace?
Ms. Aveson?
I. uh  I don't know.
You sound unsure.
She's mentioned the name.
grace Miller. in passing.
but just like any other girl
in school.
So. no. I don't know if they're
actually friends.
I guess you'll just have to ask
Cassie
when you finally get around
to locating her.
You know. I may not be a mom.
but if I were.
I think I'd know who my kid
hangs out with.
In fact. I'd probably know
everything about her life.
I'd search her room
for drugs from time to time.
because you never know
what she might be up to.
I'll take that
into consideration.
And I'll call you
if I get any more names.
Mmm.
It's her.
That was one
sneaky-ass move. Abbie.
We need to talk. I'm listening.
I don't need any long-term
trouble from you guys.
so I wanna work out a truce.
What kind of truce?
You've got 370.000.
I've got 650.000.
I'm willing to put up 150k
for you guys to back off.
Half a million for each of US.
No hard feelings.
Interested?
We're interested.
Then it's a deal.
No changing your mind.
No changing my mind.
Okay.
I'm out front of your house.
Stay on the line.
Okay. We're outside.
Where are you?
Why don't you come inside.
have a beer. talk it over?
Actually. let's do it outside.
Fine. Come here.
You guys come to me.
I've got the cash in the trunk.
All right.
Come on!
Whoa. whoa. whoa. whoa.
What the...
Little bitch.
Nick!
Stay out here!
Watch the front door!
Stop!
Open the door!
Nick?
You see her? No.
She's in here somewhere.
Aahh!
Shhh.
Oh. my God.
Shhh. It's okay.
It's okay.
Abbie. come on.
We gotta go.
We're gonna go
get your dad. so...
We just gotta get outta here.
Abbie. come on.
We gotta get out of here.
What do you think they're gonna
do when they find the bodies?
It'll look like
a drug deal gone wrong.
There are probably
20 guys out there
that would love
to see Nick dead.
So you wanna tell me
what happened?
Oh. you don't have it in you.
I  no.
Okay.
Hi. grace.
How you feeling?
Hi. Mrs. Aveson.
Uh. great.
They're gonna operate
in the morning.
Where's your mom?
She's on her way.
She had to work up in Oakland today.
Those are pretty.
Where'd you get them?
Uh. my dining room table.
Sorry. I didn't have time
to go to the florist.
But strawberry.
banana. pineapple.
with protein powder
and a vitamin dose.
Wow. How'd you know this was
my favorite?
'Cause you and Cassie always
get the same thing.
You have for years.
Where is she?
The f.B.I. Knows you were involved.
What I don't get Why would someone
like you.
about to go to one of the
top universities in the country.
want to Rob a bank?
Do you need money for tuition?
Grace. please.
tell me what's going on.
As I was driving here.
I was thinking
I should prepare some
really clever argument
to convince you to talk.
but um...
I couldn't come up
with anything.
All I know is. uh...
My husband's gone now.
Cassie's my whole life.
I make her breakfast. um...
I. uh...
On mondays. I wash her clothes.
I pay her car insurance
when she forgets.
I want to. uh...
Help pick out her classes
for college. and. uh...
I really hope
she goes to college.
I wanna see her find
a career she really loves.
and. uh...
Grace. I really wanna
see her get married.
This morning.
someone in a mask
put a gun to her head.
and I couldn't do anything.
I'm her mother.
and my job is to protect her.
and I couldn't do anything.
Is that the last time
I'm going to see her?
Oh. grace. please.
I don't know where she is.
I don't know if she's been
taken from me.
or if she's just running away
from me
or what is going on.
So please. please!
Please. grace.
just tell me what's going on.
I love her so much.
And I love you and Abbie.
I always have.
ever since you were little
and I coached you in soccer.
Remember that?
We never won one game. but we
had a lot of fun. right?
Please.
I am so sorry about all this.
I  I can't say anything.
but if it's any help.
just know this whole thing
will be over in 45 minutes.
That's 4:00.
What's happening
at 4:00?
Coyote pass. off of highway 98.
They're going to the desert.
Grace. why?
Why are they going there?
I can't say.
Abbie. what did you do?
4:00. Don't be
late. or I chop off his head.
There it is. Right up there.
Okay. It's gotta be down there.
Cassie!
Mom?
Oh. my God!
Are you okay?
How did you find
US? It wasn't easy.
What are you doing here?
I want the truth. You need to leave.
Why? What is going on?
They can't see you.
They'll think it's a trap.
She's right. mom. "They"? Who's they?
Girls. I am not budging. so you
better just spit it out.
What is going on?
All right. Abbie's dad
was kidnapped in Tijuana.
and the kidnappers
are gonna be here any minute.
What? They told me that
I had to give them
a half a million dollars
or they would kill him.
That's why I robbed the
bank. She's telling the truth. mom.
Did you help her? No. I had no idea
she was doing any of this until today.
Please. don't hate me. Ms. Aveson.
My mom is gone. and my dad is broke.
I couldn't tell the cops.
What else could I do?
What would you do?
Mom. you really have to leave
right now.
This is mendoza.
Code 10-31.
I'm at the end of coyote
pass trail off highway 98.
I'm gonna need backup.
Code 10-31.
Please. Mrs. Aveson.
my dad's life depends on it.
We need to get outta here now. We'll
call the police. They'll handle it. Come on.
No. I'm not leaving
without my dad!
You and Cassie should just go
and get outta here.
No. we all go together.
No. I'm staying.
You're always bugging me to have
some kind of ambition. right?
To believe in something.
Well. Abbie is my best friend. Oh. jeez.
If I walk out on her at a time like
this. what kind of a woman am I?
You are gonna be a dead woman.
and none of that idealistic
garbage that I taught you
will mean anything.
do you hear me?
Let's go. both of you!
Who are you?
This is my friend and her mom.
I told you to come
alone. You a cop?
No. I'm just here
to help Abbie.
Chaperones.
Pretty ones.
You got the money?
It looks like a million to me.
Senorita Duncan.
it was a pleasure
doing business with you.
Maybe we do it again
sometime. yes?
Mendoza. do you copy?
Who's there?
Who else you bring?
Federal agents!
Drop your weapons!
Drop your weapons now!
Now! You're
completely surrounded!
Ms. Aveson. get down.
Get your people
behind me now. Come on. Come on.
Where are the other police?
Turn around.
You alone. 'señora'?
Shut up and turn around!
Get down on your knees now!
I don't see nobody.
What happened to your police
friends? They forget about you?
Turn around. now!
No! Miguelito!
Miguelito.
Miguelito!
He's getting away! Let him go.
Get outta here!
Get outta here now!
Go!
I'll get those gringos!
Mom!
Give me that.
So you're my
pretty little bank robber. huh?
I know what
my daughter did was wrong.
She didn't mean to hurt anybody.
She doesn't deserve
to go to jail.
Please.
She's all I have left.
Is there something you can do?
Is this the weapon you
used in the bank robbery?
Well. is it. or not?
Who does the gun belong to?
Nobody.
It's black market.
It can't be traced.
Are you prepared
to make a statement
that those were the three guys
that kidnapped you this morning?
Oh...
I want you to think about
what I'm asking you. Cassie.
Yes.
Come on.
Easy.
Careful. Careful.
I still have some
contacts in Tijuana.
I'm gonna say I got a tip
the robbers were here.
making their way to the border.
What's that?
Look at the surveillance
video at the bank.
You'll see.
Come on.
Thank you.
I never wanna
see your face again.
Agent mendoza. you copy?
Mendoza. We're 15 minutes out.
I'm gonna need a 10-52.
Copy that. All right.
The three of you
need to get out outta here.
You. too. I'm staying
with my daughter.
If I'm gonna pin this bank job on those
three guys. you're gonna need to leave.
Look. you have no idea what I have
gone through to try and find her today.
and if you think for one second
Mom!
I'm gonna be okay.
I guess you will be.
Hey. can I ask you a question?
Yeah.
If you were in Abbie's situation
and someone you loved
was kidnapped.
and you had to get ahold
of a million dollars.
what would you do?
Me?
I'd probably Rob a bank.
---oOo---